Contact

dominion.green@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/adriandgreen (LinkedIn) adriangreen.xyz (Personal)

Top Skills

Responsive Web Design Generative AI Code Generation

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Learning React.js

Publications

www.adriangreen.xyz

Adrian Green

Head of Technology @ Distro Nation

Norfolk, Virginia, United States

Summary

I'm a passionate front/back-end web developer with twelve years of industry experience.

My entire career in IT has spanned more than two decades beginning with a high school

internship and network analyst roles during my college years.

A self-taught web dev, I have followed my dreams working for small to large

organizations proving capable of deploying solutions that minimize cost

and maximize value.

Experience

Distro Nation Head of Technology February 2024 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Live Nation Entertainment Software Engineering Lead February 2016 - February 2024 (8 years 1 month) Greater New York City Area

After the acquisition of INDMusic by Live Nation I was the sole staff developer of Live Nation (Distro Nation) and directed the technological vision as we expanded into wider digital distribution across all major streaming platforms.

Key Responsibilities

- Spearheaded the frontend development of Live Nation's Video Network, integrating analytics, rich media, and custom UIs for major streaming platforms.
- Built responsive React components that streamlined video content distribution for audiences spanning millions of users.

- Collaborated with product, design, teams to prototype and deploy clientfacing solutions utilized by third party vendors. This includes geo-fencing applications that facilitated real time comms with music festival attendees.
- Orchestrated microservices hosted on AWS (ECS, Lambda, S3), ensuring seamless integration with frontend components and optimized build pipelines for faster feature delivery.
- Created dynamic interfaces in Codesandbox for iterative review; upon approval, facilitated migrations to AWS Amplify or ECS for scalable production environments.
- Established a robust social analytics database to track and display audience metrics in real-time, enabling data-driven decisions and boosting partner satisfaction.

INDMUSIC

Head of Technology November 2013 - 2016 (3 years) Brooklyn, NY

INDMusic was a pioneer in monetizing independent artists' music on the YouTube platform. As the sole developer, I was key to establishing them as a player in the YouTube Multichannel Network space

Key Responsibilities

Designed and managed a lifecycle accounting system capable of parsing large reports and efficiently allocating client funds based on ownership splits.

Developed and maintained an authenticated administrative CMS and clientfacing financial dashboard, ensuring seamless access to relevant financial information.

Explored and implemented 3rd party integrations to enhance client offerings and automate internal functions, streamlining operations and improving efficiency.

Accomplishments

Significantly accelerated client acquisition by implementing a scalable reporting infrastructure, successfully parsing large CSV files into readable and fully transparent streaming royalty reports.

Leveraged APIs of external mail services to power a customizable client newsletter tool, enabling personalized accounting updates and communications.

Collaborated on the creation of custom analytics dashboards for record labels, facilitating the identification of new artists with increased audience engagement and providing actionable insights to capitalize on their popularity.

Maersk Line, Limited Senior Network Analyst 2008 - November 2013 (5 years) Norfolk, Virginia, United States

Windows Server 2003/2008 administration and group policy management.

Key Responsibilities

Managed software and hardware installations and upgrades on remote shipping container vessels, ensuring smooth operations and optimal performance.

Conducted hardware installations aboard container vessels and assisted in establishing connections to satellite communications, ensuring seamless connectivity.

Tested and orchestrated the distribution of regular Windows updates via Windows Software Update Service, maintaining system security and stability.

Accomplishments

Implemented scripted automation into the team workflow, significantly boosting productivity through remotely triggered software installations and upgrades.

Led daily stand-up meetings, effectively organizing pending tasks and fostering a sense of unity and teamwork within the team.

Independently researched, tested, and deployed administrative software after obtaining approval, resulting in the deployment of a cost-saving software solution capable of alerting hardware failures on remote vessels.

Shipboard Technologies Ship Support Analyst July 2008 - November 2009 (1 year 5 months) Recruiter hooks me up with this job at Maersk as a contractor. Its amazing - I always wanted to work in Downtown Norfolk since I was a little kid. I get to this job and I can hit the ground running especially since I was learning Autolt on the low. I tried to put them on to that but they weren't ready, no fault to them.

So my contractor period came up and we had already been working with Shipboard Tech just through Maersk. They offer to have me work for them so I can have a more stable position at the company and it worked great. Shout out to the Shipboard Tech team because they looked out and didn't have to. I was still on my young boi stuff so I had to grow up even more with these cats. These were not with any nonsense which led to some friction but nothing but respect.

Blah blah...

Ship Support Analyst

Working for Shipboard Technologies as a contractor, provided network engineering, analysis, and troubleshooting services aboard Maersk commercial container vessels.

Assisted in planning the deployment of new custom software engineered in Copenhagen to all U.S. Ships in the Maersk fleet. This included customizing each program in order to fit U.S. Ships more cohesively.

While working for Shipboard Technologies I became accustomed to traveling in and out of the country and working under narrow time constraints.

Accomplishments: Was initially hired as a temporary employee but through hard work and organizational skills secured a permanent position as contractor for Maersk Line, Limited through Shipboard Technologies. Just finished deployment of a Sharepoint Enterprise web site to better assist the company with tracking and vessel contact information

VSD, LLC Network Administrator 2005 - 2006 (1 year)

Never did I again work with smarter people than I did at this job. The class had heavy hitters and 80% of them were better at my job than I was. I came into work every day hungry wanting to try new things on the network. This is where I got started with Group Policy and real security. Loved it - if this job asked me to work nights I was there. We once had a hardware failure and I remember LOVING restoring my network from backup tapes.

That was just the vibe there, I was young and they let me do what I had to do to learn.

I grew up a lot here.

Hamption Roads Sanitation District Desktop Analyst 2005 - 2006 (1 year)

This job was great. I got to work under a lot of dope people and I learned. I remember spending a lot of time under people's desks so thats cool to meet new people. People dont understand that helpdesk is the best way to meet new people.

So yeah this was fun - I actually came back to this job after this stint and they underutilized me. So I just got bored and spent that time researching everything I could regarding security. This also included Tor which was just popping at the time. Alas - that got me canned - so the second run at this job was wack because I had already spent time at VSD running a network. They offered me more money so I came back and was fired in less than a year I think.

Lessons Learned:

You can never go back.

Never spend that much time uninspired again.

Education

Old Dominion University BA, IT · (2003 - 2006)

Virginia Beach Technical and Career Education Center Network and System Administration/Administrator · (2010 - 2011)